我们在你脑袋里安放了微型炸弹
We've put an explosive charge in your head.
是不是听起来很熟悉？
Does that sound familiar?
兔脚在哪？
The Rabbit's Foot. Where is it?
我已经给了你
I gave it to you.
伊森 兔脚在哪？
Ethan, where's the Rabbit's Foot?
等等…你在说什么？ 难道不对吗？
Wait… What are you saying? That wasrt it?
- 我给你的 是不是… - 我数到10
- What I gave you, was that… - I'm going to count to 10.
你告诉我兔脚在哪 否则她就死了
You're going to tell me where the Rabbit's Foot is or she dies.
朱莉娅 会没事的
Jules, it's going to be okay.
会没事的 明白吗？
It's going to be okay. Do you understand?
一
One.
听我说 我有你要的东西
You listen to me. I got exactly what you asked for.
还要别的吗？
Did you want something else?
我们如果有误会 我会更正
If there was a misunderstanding, I will fix it.
你要什么我都能拿到
I can get it, whatever you want.
二
Two.
听着 我们可以谈谈
Listen. Talk to me. We can talk,
好好地谈
like gentlemen.
- 三 - 天啊！
- Three. - God!
好吧 好吧 好吧
All right. All right, all right.
我知道兔脚在哪
I know where the Rabbit's Foot is.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
就像你在飞机上对我那样？
The way you helped me on the airplane?
是那样吗？
That way?
你把枪放下 我不会这样和你讲话
You put the gun down. I'm not talking to you like this.
随你的便 四
That's your choice. Four.
兔脚在巴黎
The Rabbit's Foot's in Paris.
你想知道在巴黎什么地方？ 那就放了她
You want to know where in Paris? Then let her go.
- 因为你不能… - 它不在巴黎 五
- 'Cause you will not… - It's not in Paris. Five.
我可以给你弄来
I can get it for you.
但你要是杀了她 就什么也得不到
But you kill her, you do this, you get nothing.
- 六 - 你在没在听我说？
- Six. - Are you listening to me?
你要是想拿到你要的东西 就只能…
The only way you're going to get what you want is for you to…
- 你以为我闹着玩？ - 狗娘养的！
- Do you think I'm playing? - Son of a bitch!
你以为我闹着玩？ 你以为我做不出来？
Do you think I'm playing? You don't think I'll do it?
它在哪？到底在哪？
Where is it? Where the hell is it?
- 看着我 - 它到底在哪？
- Look at me. - Where the hell is it?
- 别离开我 - 七！七！
- Stay with me. - Seven! Seven!
我要杀了你！我向上帝发誓我要杀了你！
I am going to kill you. I swear to God I'm going to kill you!
- 八！- 不 求求你
- Eight! - No, please.
求求你 别这样 放了她吧
Please. Don't do this. Just let her go.
我向你保证
I promise you. I promise you.
- 无论你要什么我都有办法… - 九
- I can figure out how to get whatever… - Nine.
听我说 听我说
Listen to me. Listen to me.
我想帮你
I want to help you.
无论你要什么我都能帮你弄到
I want to help you get whatever you want.
但你要做得对 该怎么办你知道
But you got to do what's right. What you know is right.
不 不
No. No.
不
No.
- 十 - 不要！
- Ten. - Don't!
《碟中谍3》
- 你要干什么？ - 你弟弟还想要一瓶
- What are you doing? - Your brother wants another one.
哦 天啊 不行 伊森 我们说好了的…
Oh, God, no. Ethan, that's what we talked about…
- 我会看着他的 没事 - 瑞克就是这样
- I'm watching him. He's fine. - That's how it is with Rick.
开始没事 突然就脱光了衣服 和每个人拥抱
He's fine and then suddenly he's naked and he's hugging everybody.
- 我会对瑞克负全责的 - 是吗？全责？
- I'll take full responsibility for Rick. - You will? Full?
- 是的 基本上是 - 那责任可不小啊
- Well, mostly full. - It's a huge responsibility.
很顺利吧？
It's going well, right?
- 真的很顺利 - 嗯
- It's going really well. - Yeah.
朱莉娅 你姐姐来了
Julia, your sister's here.
- 拥抱一下 - 你真漂亮
- Give me a hug. - You look so beautiful.
我还不知道呢 这就是他？
I don't know about that. So, is this him?
- 希望如此 - 来 老天
- I hope so. - Oh, come here. Oh, gosh.
好啦 妈妈急着见你呢
All right. Mom's dying to see you.
真不敢相信你们 从弗吉尼亚大老远的赶来
I can't believe you guys came all the way to Virginia.
我们可不能错过你们订婚
Like we'd miss your engagement…
当朱莉娅打电话告诉我 她要结婚的时候
When Julia called and told me that she was getting married,
我有个想法 那就是她不能挽着爸爸的胳膊
I had one thought, that it was just too bad
走过那长廊真遗憾
that Daddy wasrt here to walk her down the aisle.
后来朱莉娅告诉我… 谢谢 妈妈
And then when Julia told me… Thanks, Mom.
告诉我伊森双亲不在了的时候
That Ethan doesn't have his parents anymore, either,
我很遗憾
I got really sad.
但是我想能组建一个新的家庭
But it occurred to me that this is about starting a new family
是多美好啊
and how beautiful that is.
我想说我要让朱莉娅当上姨妈了
And I just want to say I am making Julia an aunt,
我也盼望朱莉娅能很快让我当上姨妈
so I expect the same treatment very, very soon.
干杯！
Cheers!
运输部门？
Department of Transportation?
我在那干了10年了
I've been there over 10 years now. Wow.
你在那做什么？
What do you do at the DOT?
我研究交通模式
I study traffic patterns.
你在高速公路上踩1秒刹车再松开
You hit the brakes for a second, just tap them on the freeway,
你会发现在200英里长的公路上
you can literally track the ripple effect of that action
发生了连锁反应
across a 200-mile stretch of road,
因为交通是有记忆的
because traffic has a memory.
很令人惊奇 就像活生生的器官
It's amazing. It's like a living organism.
搀在一起喝怎么样？ 伏特加马提尼？
Freshen that up for you? What is it, vodka martini?
好的 谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
女士们 需不需要…
Ladies, do you need…
- 我想嫁给他 - 我也想
- I'd marry him. - I would, too.
那三周的跳降滑板蜜月怎么样？
Okay, so, a three-week heli-boarding honeymoon?
- 实际上你落下来… - 从直升机上
- Okay, you actually get dropped… - From a helicopter, yeah.
- 他们就是这样认识的 - 真的？
- It's how they met. - Really?
- 给她讲讲 - 没什么好讲的啦
- Tell her the story. - There's no story.
当然有的讲啊 说说吧
It is a good story. Tell the story.
首先 没人能够配得上朱莉娅
First of all, no one was ever good enough for Julia.
又来了
Oh, here we go.
不够来电 不够冒险 不够风趣…
Not spontaneous enough, adventurous enough, funny enough…
知道吗？不是那样的 就好像我从没约会过似的
You know what? No, that's not true. You make it sound like I've never dated.
没和我们喜欢的约会过
No one we liked.
- 是这样 - 是这样
- That is true. - That is true.
她坐上从湖边起飞的直升机
Then she goes and gets in a chopper that takes off from this lake…
- 那是什么湖？ - 嗯…
- What was the name of that lake? - Lake…
瓦纳卡湖 瓦纳卡
Lake Wanaka. Wanaka.
瓦纳卡 谢谢
Wanaka. Thank you.
- 他听见了？ - 他是怎么听见的？
- He heard that? - How did he hear that?
你请假三周医院没关系吧？
And the hospital's cool with you taking three weeks?
没关系的 又不是只有我一个护士
Yeah, I'm not the only nurse employed there, you know.
我就知道你会成为我姐夫的
I'm psyched that you're going to be my brother, man.
我也是 瑞克
So am I, Rick.
太神奇了 我觉得我要病了
No, it's awesome. I think it's going to be sick.
我也是 伙计 我得接个电话
Me, too, man. I just got to get the phone.
- 你很厉害 - 嗯
- You rock hard. - Okay.
喂？
Hello?
- 是伊森·亨特先生吗？ - 是的
- Is this Mr. Ethan Hunt? - Yes, it is.
我们是极速旅游服务公司
This is Ready-Travel Resort Services.
我们给您一个赢得免费墨西哥游的机会
We'd like to offer you a chance to win an all-expense-paid trip to Mexico.
我们没有冰块了 我10分钟后就回来
We ran out of ice. I'll be back in 10 minutes.
- 哦 不 不用谁跟你去吗？ - 不用了
- Oh, no. Can't somebody else go? - No, I got it.
我马上回来 你好 贝茨
I'll be right back. Hi, Betsy.
谢谢
Thank you.
1.86元
$1.86.
谢谢你能来 我不知道买多大的司乐冰
Thanks for coming. Can't decide what size Slurpee to get.
我通常是买900盎司的
I usually go for the 900-ouncer.
派对怎么样？ 很抱歉给你打了电话
How's that party? Sorry I had to call you.
- 你应该来的 - 你应该邀请我的
- Yeah, you should have come. - You should have invited me.
- 你知道我会请你去的 - 谢谢
- You know I would have. - Thanks.
我知道我们开玩笑的 但我总是求你
I know we joke about it, but I am always this close to begging you
别再训练新人 而要去执行任务
to stop training our people and get your ass back in the field.
但你不再执行任务 我也尊重你的选择
But that's not what you do anymore, and so I respect that choice.
相信我 家庭是一切
You know I do. Family's everything.
直截了当吧 约翰 什么事？
Come on, John. What's going on?
是法瑞斯特工的事
It's Agent Farris.
她在执行一个任务
She was on an operation.
突然失踪了 已失去联系11小时
She's disappeared. Been off-grid 11 hours.
我派出了搜救小组 我希望你能参加
I'm sending in Search and Rescue. I was hoping you'd want in.
你有做这事情的专家
You've got good people for that.
是啊 我们就是干这个的
Yeah. Yep, that we do.
日出时出发 如果你改变主意
Wheels up at sunrise if you have a change of heart.
给我拍几张派对的照片
Take some pictures of the party for me.
伊森 三天前
Ethan. Three days ago,
林赛·法瑞斯特工在一项 监视行动中被抓住
Agent Lindsey Farris was captured while on a surveillance operation.
这就是她正监视的人 名叫欧文·戴维安
This is the man she was tracking. His name is Owen Davian.
细节是保密的
Details are eyes-only,
但是很明确的是戴维安是黑市商人
but I can tell you that Daviars a black-market trafficker.
对我们来说是极度危险的
Extremely dangerous and a priority for us.
今天下午2点
At 1400 hours today,
侦察卫星发现了他的车队
a recon satellite ID'd a caravan of vehicles
车牌与戴维安手下的车相符
with plates matching those known to have been used by Daviars operatives.
他们停在了柏林一家废弃的工厂外面
They stopped at a derelict factory outside Berlin.
看起来他们有一名人质 我们相信那就是法瑞斯特工
It appears they have a hostage. We believe it's Agent Farris.
一般我们会否认
Normally we would disavow,
但是林赛是我们接近戴维安的关键
but Lindsey may be the key to getting us closer to Davian,
我们需要冒这个险
and that's a risk we need to take.
你的任务 如果你接受的话
Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
是找到林赛并把她带回来
is to find Lindsey and bring her home.
我已经组织了一个小队
I've already assembled a team.
我让他们待命 等你的回复
I have them standing by, awaiting your word.
这条信息 就当是给你的订婚礼物
This message, let's call it my excellent engagement gift to you,
将在5秒内自动销毁
will self-destruct in five seconds.
好运 伊森 再次感谢
Good luck, Ethan, and thanks again.
我准备好了吗？
Am I ready?
- 你没事吧？ - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
没事
Yeah.
对不起 我没告诉你 派对上办公室打来电话
You know, I'm sorry. I realized I didn't tell you that the office called
我要到休斯顿待上一夜
during the party. I have to go to Houston for a night.
那里将举行公众运输会议
METRO's having a public transpo conference.
- 现在才说啊 - 我知道
- It's so last-minute. - I know.
好啊
Well, well, well.
如果不是「不能做者 去教书」先生
Now, if it isn't Mr."Those Who Can't Do, Teach"…
回到一线来
back in the field.
- 你好吗 宝贝？ - 嘿 伙计
- What's up, baby? - Hey, man.
伊森 别担心 我们会找到那个女孩的
Hey, Ethan, don't worry. We're going to get the girl.
也许是我们分开太久 你都忘了我们有多大能耐了
Or have you been away so long you've forgotten how good we are?
欢迎回来 兄弟
Welcome back, brother.
（德国 柏林）
我们的卡车到地方了吗？
Is our truck in place?
武器准备好了？
Weapons good to go?
- 是的 你呢 - 好了
- Yeah. You? - Yeah.
我会掩护你的
You know I got your six.
嘿 伙计 那就是你的工作
Hey, man. That's your job.
一号机枪 完毕 二号机枪 完毕
Guns one, activated. Guns two, activated.
三号机枪 完毕 四号机枪 完毕
Guns three, activated. Guns four, activated.
机枪已准备好
Guns ready.
全部四挺机枪待命
All four guns operational.
他们在二楼 三楼 四楼有人
They've got men on the second, third, fourth floors.
我数了数 有14个
I count 14 of them.
监视员 我在接近位置
Observer, I'm in approach position.
收到 已准备好
Roger that. Stand by.
目标匹配
Target match.
奖品在6楼 身边两个敌人
The prize is on the sixth floor. Two Tangos with her.
进入
Moving in.
那么偷袭者一号
So, Raider One, at some point,
我们谈谈「结婚」这件事吧
we got to go over this whole "getting married" thing.
拒绝 监视员
Negative, Observer.
我们的关系还没到谈这个的地步
I don't respect you nearly enough to have that conversation.
你可以无视我
You may not respect me,
但是现在你不得不听我的声音了
but for now you're stuck with my voice in your head.
那么这个女孩 你喜欢她的什么？
So, this girl, what the hell do you see in her anyway?
谁？朱莉娅？你没见过她
Who, Julia? You've never met her.
是的 照目前这态势 永远也遇不见
Yeah, and the way things are, I probably never will.
她很幸运 对吧 你就是这样想的
Lucky for her, right? That's what you're thinking.
他们有通讯装置
They've got communications gear.
两个敌人 二楼 西北走廊
Two Tangos, second floor, northwest corridor.
土拨鼠 该你行动了
Groundhog, that's you.
我们一开战
You need to grab that gear on the second floor
你要马上夺取二楼的设备
as soon as we go hot.
收到 两分钟后准备好
Copy that. I'll need two minutes,
实际只有一分钟 对吧
which means you'll need me in one, right?
是的 差不多
Yeah, just about.
偷袭者一号 上楼梯后向左
Raider One, make a left at the top of the stairs.
奖品在大厅的尽头
The prize should be at the end of the hall.
凤凰 我看到奖品了
Phoenix, I have eye on the prize.
需要多给她10cc剂量
Give her 10 cc's more.
- 她醒过来时叫我一声 - 好
- Call me when she wakes. - Okay.
我们必须在三分钟内降落 收到？
We need touchdown in less than three. Do you copy?
收到
Roger that, I copy.
拜托 我哪次没收到？ 我做的就是收到
Please, when do I not copy? All I do is copy.
待命 收到我的信号后行动
Stand by to go live. On my mark.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一 行动
One. Execute.
警报 警报
Warning. Warning.
偷袭者一号 你安全了 行动！
Raider One, you're clear. Move!
林赛 林赛
Lindsey. Lindsey.
伊森？
Ethan?
我来带你回家
I'm going to get you home.
监视者 我拿到奖品 三分钟内撤离
Observer, I've got the prize. Evac in three.
收到
Roger that.
这是肾上腺素 林赛 可能会有点疼
This is adrenaline. Lindsey, you're going to feel this.
土拨鼠 二楼安全了
Groundhog, second floor is clear.
来了！
On the move!
监视者 我们向外走
Observer, we're on the move. Wrap out.
- 90秒内撤离 - 收到
- Evac in 90 seconds. - Roger that.
凤凰 现在去着陆地点
Phoenix, get to the LZ now.
收到 监视者 马上就到
Roger, Observer. On my way.
伊森 我有话对你说
Ethan. I have to talk to you.
- 快点 快点 - 我现在就要和你讲！
- Come on, come on. - I have to talk to you right now!
只对你一个人说 关掉对讲机
Just for you. Turn off your transmitter.
快点 伊森！
Do it, Ethan!
伊森！
Ethan!
- 林赛！快走！- 快走！
- Lindsey! Moving! - Moving!
上子弹！
Mag!
准备行动
Ready to move.
我们从这撤离
We evac from here.
蹲下！
Get down!
我没子弹了 你还剩多少？
I'm out. How many rounds you got?
足够了
Enough.
我也没子弹了
Now I'm out.
数5下
T minus five, baby.
林赛 抓紧我
Lindsey, hold on to me.
卢瑟！
Luther!
出发！
Rolling!
天啊！我的头！怎么了！
God! My head! What is that?
- 怎么回事？ - 她没事吧？
- What is… - Is she okay?
林赛！我们快上直升机
Lindsey! Let's get to the chopper.
珍 炸掉卡车
Zhen, get rid of the truck.
我们走吧
Let's go!
天啊！怎么回事！你听不到吗？
God! What is that? You can't hear that?
- 哦 天啊！- 她怎么回事？
- Oh! God! - What's wrong with her?
- 快点走！- 都上来了？
- Let's go! - We loaded?
是的！快点出发！
Yeah. Let's do it! Move out!
走！走！走！走！走！
Go, go, go, go, go!
- 狗娘养的 - 不！
- Son of a bitch. - No!
伙计们 我们有伴了 我要甩掉他们
Guys, we got company. I'm going to try and lose them.
太疼了
Hurts so much.
把它关掉
Turn it off. Please.
求求你 伊森
Please, Ethan.
伙计们 那是热追踪导弹！
Guys, their missiles are hot!
要来了！抓紧了！
Incoming! Hold on.
好了 算我们走运 但是只能有一次
Okay. That was lucky. We only get one of those.
我们有自动减颤器吗？
Do we have a defibrillator?
伊森 快关掉！
Ethan, turn it off!
开稳了！
Bring it on!
伊森！是什么？ 他们在我脑袋里放了什么？
Ethan! What is it? Did they put something in my head?
他们给你注入了定时爆炸装置
They injected you with a time-release charge.
- 你记得吗？ - 不 定时…
- Do you remember that? - No. Time-release…
爆炸物 已经激活了
An explosive. They've activated it.
除非我们烧掉电路 否则会引爆的
It's gonna detonate unless we fry the charge,
- 我们正要这么做 - 不 伊森
- which is what we're gonna do. - No, Ethan.
那样通电的话 会让她心脏停止跳动的
Zap her like that, you'll stop her heart.
然后我会再通电让她活过来
Then I'll zap her again and bring her back.
做吧！
Do it!
伙计们！他们又发射了一枚！
Guys! They're firing another one!
- 伊森！- 珍！
- Ethan! - Zhen!
珍 抓住 抓住 抓住！
Zhen, hold on. Hold on, hold on!
- 设定到150 - 150
- I want you to set it for 150. - 150.
林赛 我要让你脑袋里的炸弹短路
Lindsey, I'm gonna short out the explosive in your head.
- 你会没事的 - 需要30秒
- You're gonna be okay. - It'll need 30 seconds.
见鬼
Damn it.
- 25秒！- 快点
- Twenty-five seconds! - Come on.
快到了
We're almost there.
- 他们把我们锁定了 - 20秒
- They have us locked. - Twenty seconds.
抓紧
Hold on.
搞定他们了！
I got them!
- 10秒 - 就快好了 就快好了
- Ten seconds. - Almost there. Almost there.
给我电击板
Give me the paddles.
伊森 谢谢你
Ethan. Thank you.
妈的
Shit.
嘿
Hey.
进行得怎么样？
How did it go?
对不起 我很好 对不起
I'm sorry. Fine. I'm sorry.
我只是有点累了
I'm just tired.
我读了你关于法瑞斯特工的行动摘要
I read your training brief on Agent Farris.
你用的词是「极有能力」
The words you used were "beyond capable."
现在还这么说吗 亨特先生？
That still stand, Mr. Hunt?
- 布拉塞尔先生… - 还这么说吗？
- Mr. Brassel… - Does it stand?
是的 还是这样
Yes, sir, it does.
因为我们楼下有具尸体不这么说
Because we've got a corpse downstairs that says otherwise.
是被从鼻腔植入的炸弹
Killed by a detonator
炸死的
implanted in her skull through the nasal cavity.
布拉塞尔先生 这样评判法瑞斯特工的能力是不能接受的
Mr. Brassel, it's unacceptable to judge Agent Farris' competence based…
巧克力使你发胖也不能接受
It's unacceptable that chocolate makes you fat,
但我还是照吃不误
but I've eaten my share. And guess what?
我是通过你的评价
Now, I approved Agent Farris' surveillance op
来许可法瑞斯特工的监视任务的
based on your evaluations, Mr. Hunt,
亨特先生 一个女人让自己被抓住
of a woman who allowed herself to be captured.
然后你去营救她 遭遇了十几个人
So you go to recover her. You encounter a dozen men.
一个活口都没留下
You don't grab any of them?
我们的目标 布拉塞尔先生 是营救法瑞斯特工
Our objective, Mr. Brassel, was to recover Agent Farris.
戴维安的组织很严密
Davian employs a cellular structure at his organization.
那些人很可能不清楚…
The men there more than likely had no information…
谁得到这些结论的？是你吗？
Who's drawing these conclusions? Is it you?
- 是我 长官 是根据… - 我还没问到你呢
- I am, sir. Based upon… - I'm not on you yet.
你让法瑞斯不通过扫描就上了直升机
You allowed Farris to board your chopper without a scan.
那个炸弹可能会把你们都炸死的
That explosive device could have taken you all out.
你今天坐在这和我说话的一个原因 就是你很走运
There is one reason that you are sitting here before me today, and that is luck.
因为你们的行动计划疏忽 执行混乱
Because your operation was poorly conceived and executed worse.
- 发现了两台手提电脑 - 我知道
- Two laptops were recovered… - I'm aware of that.
我们和技术部门谈过了
We've talked to Tech Services.
他们不能保证能恢复数据
They doubt if they can reconstitute the drives.
「非常脆」 我看 是他们所说的毫无价值
"Crispy, " I believe, is what they called them. Worthless.
布拉塞尔先生 作为行动主管
Mr. Brassel, as Operation Manager of this office,
- 我有权… - 抱歉
- I have the authority… - Excuse me.
你是不是在向我施压 马斯格雷夫先生？
Did you just throw a title at me, Mr. Musgrave?
我不管你老爸和总统 打没打过高尔夫
I don't care if your daddy plays golf with the President.
这里是情报部门 我却没看见任何情报
This is Intelligence. So far I haven't seen any.
你认为这次行动冒险是值得的 亨特先生
You think this op was won'th the risk, Mr. Hunt.
你了解欧文·戴维安多少？
What do you know about Owen Davian?
就是他把浓缩铀离心分离技术
He was the one who brought gas centrifuge technology
从巴基斯坦卖到了朝鲜
to Korea from Pakistan.
还是他把毒素5号卖给了伊斯兰解放组织
He was also the man who sold Toxin Five to the Armahad Republic Jihad.
他这个人就是提供 提供 再提供！
He is a man who provides, provides, provides!
他还是隐身的 是个他妈的隐形人
And he remains invisible. He's a goddamn invisible man.
他可不是埃里森（《隐形人》的作者） 你们还想聪明点的话
Wells, not Ellison, in case you want to be cute again.
我们找不到他
We can't find him.
他明白 所以胆子很大
He knows it. It's emboldened him.
从我到这那一天起就想抓住戴维安
I've been trying to bring Davian down since the day that I got here.
你知道我为此得到了什么？
Do you know what I've got for it?
从没确认过戴维安偷了毒素5号
It's never been confirmed the Toxin Five theft was Davian.
马斯格雷夫 我说话时不要打断我
Mr. Musgrave, please don't interrupt me when I'm asking rhetorical questions.
你们的行动只有一个收获
Your operation has achieved one thing.
就是告诉戴维安他是赢家
You have reminded Davian that he is winning.
现在 我要通知法瑞斯的父母
And now, if you'll excuse me, I have to go inform Mr. And Mrs. Farris
他们的女儿在95号公路上遭遇车祸
that their baby girl was killed in a head-on collision on l-95.
我今天在这沉痛地
I stand here today deeply saddened
为一位上帝的子民的死而哀悼
by the death of one of God's children,
林赛·伊丽莎白·法瑞斯
Lindsey Elizabeth Farris.
上帝意想不到地带走这样一个 年轻的生命很令人吃惊
It is always startling when the Lord takes one of our young so unexpectedly.
要有侵略性 集中注意力 膝盖弯曲 很好 很好
Be aggressive. Come on. Stay focused. Keep your knees bent. Good. Good.
扣动扳机 退子钩就要…
Now, to fire the lock, the extractor has to be…
沙包不会反击的 更用力些
That bag's not going to hit you back. Hit harder.
别依赖视觉 眼睛盯着你的目标
Don't rely on your sights. Keep your eyes dead on the target…
攻击我 来吧
Attack me. Come on.
用不要释放撞针除非退子钩…
Don't ever release the firing pin unless the extractor's…
很好 就这样 很好
Good. There you go. Good.
确认目标 瞄准 射击 很简单 瞄准 射击
Identify the target. Point and shoot. It's very simple. You point and shoot.
集中注意力
Stay focused.
法瑞斯小姐 你知道 我已训练过多少新兵
Miss Farris, you know how many recruits I've trained.
我很自豪地说你是第一个
I'm proud to say that you are the first
我推荐到一线服役的
that I've recommended for active field duty.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
我准备好了吗？
Am I ready?
喂？
Yes?
是凯尔文先生吗？
Is this Mr. Kelvin?
是的 您是哪位？
Yes. Who is this?
这里是诺福克邮政服务
I'm calling from Norfolk Mail Service.
林赛·法瑞斯在这租了个邮箱
Lindsey Farris rents a post office box here.
她从柏林给你寄来一个邮件
She sent you a piece of mail from Berlin
邮件到达时要我们通知你
and asked us to call you when it arrived.
今天早晨到的
It came this morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 就是这个 - 谢谢
- This right here. - Thanks.
是个微粒照片
It's a microdot.
上面什么都没有 很奇怪
A microdot with nothing on it. This is unusual.
林赛不会寄给我空的微粒照片
Lindsey wouldn't send me a blank microdot.
我告诉你了 伙计 上面是空的
I'm telling you, man, there's no image.
那你是看错了地方
Then you're not looking in the right place.
那他妈我应该看哪？
Where the hell am I supposed to look?
这东西没有多大
There's not much square footage to this thing.
为何林赛会寄给我空的微粒照片？
Why would Lindsey send me a blank microdot?
不知道 为何林赛会寄给你东西？
I don't know. Why would Lindsey send you anything?
你是她的教官 不是联系人
You were her instructor, not her handler.
听着 伙计 我不想过线
Listen, man. I don't mean to cross the line,
但你们之间是不是有什么事？
but was there something going on between you two?
你和林赛
You and Lindsey.
林赛就像我的妹妹
Lindsey was like my little sister.
那你从没
And you never
和你妹妹睡过？
slept with your little sister, right?
嘿 老兄 如果我不问你 谁还会问？
Hey, brother, if I don't ask you, who will?
也许这东西是磁性材料
Maybe it's magnetic. The microdot.
那早就过时了
Well, that's old school.
如果她很紧迫 只能到黑市弄货是有可能的
If she was in a hurry and only had access to black-market gear, maybe.
- 你有没有办法读出来？ - 我认识个家伙也许行
- Could you get the tools to read it? - I might know a guy.
- 磁性意味着那是加密的 - 是的 我知道
- Magnetic means encrypted. - Yeah, I know that.
好 我这就过去
Yeah. Be right there.
林赛吸引人的地方是很单纯
The thing about Lindsey is she was brand-new.
那叫可爱 你还记得你可爱的时候吗？
She was sweet. Remember when you were sweet?
- 你能回忆到那么久之前吗？ - 嗯 很难
- Can you remember that far back? - Yeah, well, barely.
在德国 你问我喜欢朱莉娅哪点
In Germany, you asked me what it is I see in Julia.
我在朱莉娅身上看到的 就是这一切之前的生活
What I see in Julia is life before all this.
那很美好
And it's good.
班吉 有什么收获？
Benji, what have you got?
那些硬盘都烧焦了
Well, these hard drive platters are just fried.
- 嗯 - 你知道 那简直是一团糟
- Yeah. - You know, they made a mess of them.
就像… 上面千疮百孔了
It's just like… There's holes in them and stuff.
并且全都烧焦了 还有…
And it's got scorched all the way through. And then…
看 这个上面有个洞
Look, this one's got a hole in it and stuff.
我相信不了 连看都没法看
I can't believe. I can't even look at it.
- 班吉 你发现什么了吗？ - 是的 是的
- Benji. Did you recover anything? - Yes. Yes.
尽管从你那来的硬盘 有上面那些问题
Despite the aforementioned conditions of the hard drive you brought back,
我还是能恢复一部分邮件
I managed to recover portions of two dozen e-mail files.
这让我相信
Also made what I believe to be
是个重大的升职的机会
a thoroughly promotion-won'thy breakthrough.
你的戴维安先生将于后天到达罗马
Your Mr. Davian is going to arrive in Rome the day after tomorrow
出席一个梵蒂冈的典礼
and attend a function at one Vatican City.
戴维安他妈的到梵蒂冈去干什么？
What the hell is Davian doing at the Vatican?
肯定和「兔脚」有关
It's all got to do with the "Rabbit's Foot."
兔脚？
Rabbit's Foot?
我估计就像是个代号
Yeah, well, I'm assuming it's like a code word
来表示将要卖给一个不明买家的什么东西
for something he's about to sell to an unspecified buyer,
值8亿5千万 或许也不是个代号
for $850 million, by the way. Or maybe it's not a code word.
也许是个真正的贵重的兔子脚
Maybe it's just a really, really expensive bunny appendage.
你不知道是什么？
You have no idea what it is?
真有趣 我认识个牛津大学的教授
It's interesting. I used to have this professor at Oxford, okay?
维克汉姆博士 他的名字就这样 他就像个肥佬
Dr. Wickham, his name was, and he was like this massive, fat guy.
就是那种很大块头的家伙 我们称他…
You know, huge, big guy. We used to call him…
嗯…我还是不告诉你我们怎么称呼他了
You know… Well, I won't tell you what we used to call him.
他教生物分子动力学和细胞动力学
He taught biomolecular kinetics and cellular dynamics,
他经常用
and he used to sort of scare the underclassmen
世界如何被科技毁灭的故事
with this story about how the world would eventually be eviscerated
吓唬学生
by technology.
你看 一种化合物被不可避免地创造
You see, it was inevitable that a compound would be created,
他称之为「反上帝」
which he referred to as the "Anti-God."
有点像那种加速的变异器
It was like an accelerated mutator, a sort of, you know,
像是不能阻止的毁灭性力量
like an unstoppable force of destructive power
把一切都毁掉
that would just lay waste to everything.
建筑 公园 街道 儿童
To buildings and parks and streets and children
还有冷饮店
and ice cream parlors, you know?
所以每当我发现一个犯罪组织
So whenever I see, like, a rogue organization,
要花一大笔钱在一项神秘的技术上
willing to spend this amount of money on a mystery tech,
我总是假设那是反上帝的
I always assume it's the Anti-God.
有点像世界末日的样子 知道吗？
End-of-the-world kind of stuff, you know?
但我不是很清楚 我只是假设
But, no, I don't have any idea what it is. I was just speculating.
- 你告诉马斯格雷夫了吗？ - 谁 我？还没有
- Did you brief Musgrave on this? - Who, me? No, not yet.
- 很好 别告诉他 - 什么？
- Good. Don't. - What?
- 别告诉任何人 - 我可是花了好大力气的
- Don't tell anyone about this. - This took me ages.
如果行动失败了
If something goes wrong with the operation,
我要让马斯格雷夫毫不知情
I want Musgrave to have deniability.
- 干得好 班吉 - 什么行动？
- That's great work, Benji. - What operation?
你那个眼神说明我又要遭罪了吧
That look in your eye is a pain in my ass.
你知道的吧
You know that, right?
请空闲的住院医生到儿科来
Any available resident to Pediatrics.
康复护理 打电话给药房
Rehabilitative Care, call the pharmacy.
康复护理 打电话给…
Rehabilitative Care, call the…
我又要出去了
I have to go away again.
公干 两天
On business. Two days.
两天？
Two days?
嗯
Yeah.
伊森 怎么了？
Ethan, what's going on?
我一直以为你只是需要时间
I keep thinking you just need time
来告诉我…
to tell me whatever it is that it's…
但我弄不明白
But nothing in my mind makes sense.
嗯
Yeah.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你有什么没告诉我？
What are you not telling me?
我要你答应我
I need to ask you for something.
是最…
And it's the most…
我要你相信我
I need you to trust me.
我当然相信你
Of course I trust you.
我还会弄明白吗？
Am I ever going to be able to understand what this is?
我要你相信我
I need you to trust me.
嗯
Yes.
我相信你
I trust you.
是…
Is it…
告诉我这是真的
Tell me it's real.
我是说我们
I mean us.
告诉我这是真的
Tell me it's real.
跟我来
Follow me.
你们将要许下的誓言
The vows you're about to take
将是经过慎重思考过的
are not to be taken without careful thought and prayer.
爱情不因困难的环境减损
This love is not to be diminished by difficult circumstances
只会因死亡而消逝
and it is only to be dissolved by death.
你们有戒指吗？
Do you have the rings?
是的
Yeah.
跟我念
Repeat after me.
我 朱莉娅·安妮·米德…
I, Julia Anne Meade…
愿以伊森·马修·亨特…
…hereby take Ethan Matthew Hunt…
作为我合法的丈夫
…to be my lawfully wedded husband.
明天可能是我们唯一一个
Tomorrow may be the only time we can predict
能预测欧文·戴维安位置的机会
where Owen Davian is going to be.
慈善活动 梵蒂冈
Charity event. Vatican City.
我们的任务是潜入并绑架戴维安
Our mission is to get in and kidnap Davian.
我不知他为什么这么高兴
I don't know why he's so happy.
我提醒过他梵蒂冈就是梵蒂冈
I did remind him that the Vatican is the Vatican.
罗马城中心的109英亩的主权国
A 109-acre sovereign state in the middle of Rome,
被60英尺的高墙围绕 超过200个摄像头
surrounded by a 60-foot wall, which is monitored 24/7,
全天候监视
with over 200 CCTV cameras.
这还不是有挑战性的地方
That's not even what makes it a challenge.
抓住戴维安很好 但是抓住他的买家更好
Getting Davian is good. But getting his buyers is even better.
如果他们意识到他被抓住 就不会出现了
If they realize he's been grabbed, they'll disappear.
对不起 你说什么？
I'm sorry, what are you saying?
无论我们怎样抓住戴维安
No matter how we grab Davian,
他的客户都会知道的
his clients are gonna know he's been taken.
不 不会的 入口在这里
No, they won't. Access point is here.
靠近梵蒂冈城墙有一条单行路
It's a one-way street adjacent to the Vatican wall.
我要用30秒时间 我们需要一辆卡车
I'll need 30 seconds. And we'll need a truck.
（意大利 罗马）
现在我们激怒了罗马城的每个人
Now we've pissed off every Italian in Rome,
按计划行动
go do what you got to do.
- 别忘了烟雾 - 嗯
- Don't forget the smoke. - Yeah.
「矮胖子 墙上坐」
"Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall."
A组 这里是B组 正按计划行事
Alpha team, this is Bravo. Right on schedule.
我们应60秒内进入
We should have breach in 60.
收到 C组 报告
Roger that. Charlie team, report.
我还真没什么可报告的
Well, I don't have anything to report, really.
除了我看我能赶上时间以外
Except I think I should be right on time.
我们在等你呢
We'll be waiting for you.
- 还需两分钟时间 - 收到
- ETA two minutes. - Roger that.
C组 发射追踪器了吗？
Charlie team, did you fire the tracer yet?
马上就做
Stand by.
现在发射追踪器
Firing the tracer. Now.
A组 我进入了 倒计时2分钟
Alpha, I'm in. T minus two minutes.
收到
Roger that.
C组 我看到你了
Charlie team, I see you.
我在循环播放保安监视录像 待命准备进入
I'm looping the security feed. Stand by to move.
收到
Roger that.
录像已经循环 行动
Video is looped. Go.
A组 地下监视录像搞定了吗？
Alpha team, catacomb video taken care of?
搞定了 可以行动
Taken care of. We're good to go.
- D组 收到了吗？ - 收到
- Delta team, do you copy? - All I do is copy.
真有趣 准备进入位置
That's funny. Get ready to move into position.
- 我已经到了 - 真的？
- I'm already there. - Really?
还需30秒
ETA 30 seconds.
30秒后见
See you in 30.
A组正进入位置
Alpha team moving into position.
B组待命准备传送信号
Bravo standing by for transmission.
传送
Transmitting.
找到了
Got you.
奥尼娅·德米娅小姐
Miss Onia Demea.
我应该在名单上的 谢谢
I should be on the list. Thank you.
对不起 上面没有你的名字
I'm sorry. Your name is not here.
一定出了什么差错
There must be some mistake.
德米娅小姐？
Miss Demea?
等一下
Just a minute.
她成功了
She made it.
我们有个拍照的机会
We have a photo opportunity.
我在候命中
Just give me the word. I'm standing by.
D组 准备上传
Delta, ready for upload.
D组 下载顺利
Delta team, download good.
听着 伙计 我那天关于你订婚的的事
Listen, man, I didn't mean to be so cavalier the other day
说的不中听的话并非本意
about you getting engaged.
我知道 谢谢
I know that. Thanks.
但是普通的爱情 并不适合我们这样的人
But a normal relationship isn't viable for people like us.
- 我不同意 - 那我就比你聪明
- I don't agree with that. - Then I'm smarter than you.
我要上去了 我同意卢瑟的话
I'm going up. I agree with Luther.
我们不能有真正的爱情 但你看 我喜欢留情
We can't have real relationships. But you see, I love that.
23个月 最长也就这样了
Twenty-three months. That's as long as it'll last
我们的生活方式会成为累赘
when you got the baggage we do and the lifestyle we got.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Really? - Yeah, really.
看着我 我知道我在说什么
Look at me. I know what I'm talking about.
你也知道我在说什么
And you know I know what I'm talking about.
在这等着
Wait here.
戴维安拿起了一个公文箱
Davian just picked up a briefcase.
我们得加快行动了
We're going to have to move sooner than we thought.
- 你能确认谁放下的皮箱吗？ - 不能 你们进行得怎么样了？
- Can you identify who made the drop? - Negative. How close are you guys?
正在印模
We're just printing now.
我不自豪 我也不喜欢
I'm not proud of it. I'm not happy about it,
但是我有过几次和女人生活的经历
but I've lived with women a few times,
没有超过两年的
and it doesn't ever make it to two years.
- 你也做不到 - 多谢你的建议
- You can't. - Thanks for the advice,
但是我和你不同
but it's different for me than it is for you, you know?
- 我不会在一线服役了 - 那好
- I'm not in the field anymore. - Oh, okay.
这是退休礼物
Here's a retirement present.
在我们的工作里 你总和女人有牵连
In our job, there's always going to be something between you and a woman.
总是这样
Always.
- 卢瑟 听着 - 不诚实
- Luther, listen. - Dishonesty.
不诚实会坏了一切
A dishonesty that poisons everything.
我得告诉你一件事…
I think I need to tell you something…
别说了 这不仅仅关于你
Stop talking. This isn't about you, Ethan.
无论那女孩是谁 你都会搞砸还把她的性命搭上
And whoever this girl is, you're going to end up messing up her life, too.
别这么做
Don't do it.
朱莉娅和我两天前结婚了
Jules and I got married two days ago.
恭喜啊
Congratulations.
谢谢 谢谢
Thanks. Thanks.
- 他在走动 我过去了 - 收到
- He's walking. I'm going in. - Roger that.
我这就来
I'm on my way.
女士 我要你后退几步
Ma'am. I need you to step back.
没事 没事 没事
No. It's fine. It's fine. It's fine.
我总是把红酒洒在订做的白衬衣上
I always spill red wine on my white custom-made shirt.
- 好的 后退几步 - 没事的 我要去洗手间
- Okay. Step back. - It's fine. It's fine. Bathroom.
告诉我你快到了
Tell me you're on your way.
我在赶过去
I'm on the move.
快点
Move it. Come on.
他的保镖正检查洗手间
His bodyguards are checking out the bathroom.
我就快到了
I'm almost there.
他进去了
He's going in.
安静 念这个
Quiet. Read this.
慢慢念
Slowly.
念
Read it.
「巴兹比的陪伴
"The pleasure of Buzby's company
是我最喜欢的
is what I most enjoy.
他放了一枚大头针 在杨西小姐的椅子上
He put a tack on Miss Yancy's chair
她说他是个坏孩子
when she called him a horrible boy.
那个月末他扔了两只小猫
At the end of the month he was flinging two kittens
从房间这边到那边
across the width of the room.
我指望他的计划透露…「
I count on his schemes to reveal the…"
- 这他妈是什么 - 念完
- What the hell is this? - Finish.
A组 要有访客来了
Alpha, you're about to have a visitor.
念完！
Finish!
「摆脱阴郁的方法」
"…a way to escape my gloom."
好了
Got it.
A组 收到了吗？ 保镖要进去了
Alpha, do you copy? The guard's on his way.
D组 截住他 我还要点时间
Delta, stall him. I need more time.
太晚了 他进入走廊了
It's too late for that. He's in the hallway.
先生 没事吧？
Sir, is everything all right?
还没搞定 语音掩饰正在编译中
Everything is not all right. Voice mask is still compiling.
需要30秒
I need 30 seconds.
先生？
Sir?
6秒 正在上传
Six seconds, I'm uploading.
- 摆脱阴郁的方法 - 好了
- A way to escape my gloom. - Okay. Go.
我没事 到外面等着
I'm fine. Wait outside.
下水道见
See you in the sewer.
- 她很抱歉您的衬衫 - 没关系
- She's sorry about your shirt. - That's no problem.
她的宾馆有洗衣服务 她很乐意给您洗干净
Her hotel has laundry service, and she'll happily take care of it.
你想洗我的衬衫？
You want to wash my shirt?
我们在你房间里 我没穿衬衫
What are we going to do while we're waiting in your hotel room,
等着的时候能做什么呢？
and I'm not wearing my shirt?
她会想点事情做
She'll think of something.
她很乐意开车
She would like to drive.
跟我去宾馆
Follow me to the hotel.
先生 需要我们看着手提箱吗？
Sir, would you like us to watch the case?
不用了
No.
- 干得漂亮 - 谢谢
- Nice job. - Thank you.
- 怎么了？ - 没事 你怎么了？
- What's up? - Nothing. What's up with you?
没事
Nothing.
炸掉汽车
Blow the car.
那可是辆好车啊
Oh. It's such a nice car.
没办法 炸吧
And yet, do it.
马斯格雷夫先生要见您
Mr. Musgrave to see you.
让他进来
Send him in.
伊森·亨特和他的小队 刚刚在罗马抓住了欧文·戴维安
Ethan Hunt and his team just grabbed Owen Davian in Rome.
他们正在往回赶 我以为你知道的
They're headed back now. I thought you should know.
你很清楚这次行动？
You were aware of this operation?
是的
Yes, I was.
干得不错
Then good work.
谢谢
Thank you.
你已经死了 戴维安
You're dead, Mr. Davian.
有见证人在场
There were witnesses.
就是你在洗手间里
That was you in the bathroom.
现在 你得把一切都告诉我们
Now, you're going to tell us everything.
和你合作的每个买家 每个组织
Every buyer you've worked with. Every organization.
你他妈叫什么？
What the hell is your name?
姓名 合同 详细目录
Names, contacts, inventory lists.
你有老婆吧 还是女友？
You have a wife, girlfriend?
下面怎么样取决于你
It's up to you how this goes.
因为你知道我要怎么办
Because you know what I'm going to do next?
无论她是谁 我都要找到她
I'm going to find her, whoever she is,
我要找到她 并折磨她
I'm going to find her, and I'm going to hurt her.
我们清楚你知道
You were apprehended carrying details
代号兔脚的东西的下落
of the location of something code named the Rabbit's Foot.
我要让她流血 叫喊 喊你的名字
I'm going to make her bleed, and cry, and call out your name.
你无能为力 知道为什么吗？
And you're not going to be able to do shit. You know why?
兔脚是什么？
What is the Rabbit's Foot?
因为你就快要死了
Because you're going to be this close to dead.
还有买家是谁？
And who is the buyer?
我要在她面前杀了你
And then I'm going to kill you right in front of her.
- 我再问你一次 - 你叫什么？
- I'm going to ask you one more time. - What's your name?
- 兔脚是什么？ - 你是谁？
- What is the Rabbit's Foot? - Who are you?
买家是谁？
And who is the buyer?
你还不知道这是怎么回事吧
You don't have any idea what the hell is going on, do you?
我是说你看到我对你的 金发美女朋友在工厂里做了什么吧
I mean, you saw what I did to your little blonde friend at the factory, right?
那没什么 那只是
Well, that was nothing. That was
好玩
fun.
只是好玩
That was fun.
兔脚是什么？
What is the Rabbit's Foot?
- 伊森！- 兔脚是什么？
- Ethan! - What is the Rabbit's Foot?
伊森 住手！
Ethan, stop!
是什么？
What is it?
别这么做！
Don't do it!
- 伊森！- 兔脚是什么？
- Ethan! - What is the Rabbit's Foot?
快告诉我！
You tell me!
伊森 住手！别这样
Ethan, stop! Don't do it.
这不是你！这不是你！
This isn't you, man! This isn't you!
我们可以利用他 伊森！你知道的！
We can use him, Ethan! You know that!
不 伊森！别这么做！
No, Ethan! Don't do it!
求求你 快住手！
Please, stop!
我卖的东西
What I'm selling,
还有卖给谁
and who I'm selling to,
是你最不应该关心的
is the last thing you should be concerned about,
伊森
Ethan.
伊森 我们搞定了 林赛的微粒照片
Ethan, we got it. Lindsey's microdot.
那是个视频文件
It's a video file.
伊森 我不知道他们跟你说了什么 我不知道你怎么想的
Ethan, I don't know what they've told you. I don't know what you think.
听我说
Just listen to me.
布拉塞尔派我到德国监视一笔交易
Brassel sent me to Germany to surveil an exchange,
确认一个叫欧文·戴维安的人的身份
to ID a man named Owen Davian.
我窃听了他的电话 拦截了传送的信息
I tagged his phone, and I intercepted a transmission.
我通过IMF网络追查电话来源
I traced the call through the IMF network, and this is what came up.
那是从布拉塞尔的办公室打过去的
The call to Davian came from Brassel's office.
就是布拉塞尔 我想他在和戴维安合作
It's Brassel. I think he's working with Davian.
我被下了套
I think I'm being set up…
伊森！
Ethan!
你没事吧？
You all right?
快打电话请求支援！
Someone call for help!
有人带了手机吗？
Does anyone have a cell phone?
大家趴下！
Everybody, get down!
趴下！趴下 快趴下！大家都趴下！
Get down! Get down, get down! Everybody, get down!
- 那边有位女士中枪了 - 我看到了
- There's a woman down. - I see her.
趴下！趴下！别起来！
Get down! Get down! Stay down!
大家趴下！快趴下！别站起来！
Everybody, get down! Get down! Stay down!
趴下！
Get down!
打开车门！
Open up!
打开车门！我要控制囚犯！
Open up! I need the prisoner!
天啊！
Oh, my God!
我在流血 别离开我 好吗？
It's really bleeding. Don't leave me, okay?
放心吧 我就在你身边
Don't worry. I'm right here.
伊森我们的车里有把G36！
Ethan, there's a G36 in the truck!
我知道！我知道！
I know! I know!
让无人巡逻飞机待命 囚车里有个IMF探员
Turn the drone around. There's an IMF agent in the truck.
伊森！快出来！
Ethan! Get out of the truck!
伊森快点出来！
Ethan, move!
- 喂？ - 瑞克 我是伊森 朱莉娅在家吗？
- Hello? - Rick, this is Ethan. Is Julia home?
伙计 听着 我希望你能冷静听我说 我在家 但是…
Hey, man. Look, I hope you're not mad I'm here. It's just…
瑞克我没事 朱莉娅到底在家吗？
Rick, I'm not mad. Is Julia home?
我打过她手机了但只有留言信箱
I tried her cell phone, and there was no answer.
很抱歉 她不在 对了 你的那位朋友找到你了吗？
No. Sorry. Hey, did your friend find you?
什么朋友？
Which friend?
我也不认识 只是一个操英国口音的人
I don't know. Just some English guy.
瑞克 你跟他说了些什么？
Rick, what did you tell him?
听着伙计 我告诉他我也不知道你在哪
Look, it's all good, man. I told him I didn't know where you were,
他可能 也应该会去医院找朱莉娅
and Julia might, and he should just try her at the hospital.
喂？
Hello?
- 好的 莎莉明天见 - 恩 晚安 亲爱的
- All right, see you tomorrow, Sally. - All right. Good night, honey.
嗨 我是朱莉娅 请留言…
Hi. It's Julia. Please leave me a message…
…今天4点 切萨皮克海湾大桥 双向的车道都关闭了
…at 4:00 today, the Chesapeake Bay Bridge is closed in both directions.
- 6层 - 莎莉我是伊森
- Sixth floor. - Sally, this is Ethan.
- 我要跟朱莉娅谈谈 - 嗨 亲爱的
- I need to talk to Julia. - Hey, honey.
她刚去楼下了 我帮你转过去
She just went downstairs. I'll transfer you.
该死的！
Damn it!
您好 请问
Excuse me.
你知道哪能找到这个病人么？
I was wondering if you knew where I might find this patient.
我不太清楚 但我知道谁可以帮到你
Probably not. But I'll know who can.
那是什么？
What's that?
莎莉 朱莉娅在哪？
Sally. Where's Julia?
- 朱莉娅在哪？ - 我想她走了
- Where's Julia? - I think she left.
你去东楼找过了么？
Have you tried the east building?
- 朱莉娅走了么？ - 我没见过她
- Has Julia left yet? - I haven't seen her.
- 迈克 迈克 你见过朱莉娅吗？ - 嗨 你还好吗？
- Mike, Mike. Have you seen Julia? - Hey, you okay?
- 见过朱莉娅吗？ - 没有
- Have you seen Julia? - No.
伙计 小心点
Watch it, buddy!
- 朱莉娅？ - 你把我挂在飞机外面
- Jules? - You hung me outside of an airplane.
你也应该能看得出我是个有个性的人
You can always tell someone's character
我觉得他们对待某些人好得有些过分了
by the way they treat those they don't need to treat well.
- 如果你敢伤害她 我发誓… - 别威胁我 千万别这么做
- Lf you hurt her, I swear… - Don't threaten me. Just don't.
我在罗马捡到的公文包 就是你从我这拿走的那个
The briefcase I picked up in Rome, the one you took from me,
里面记录了兔脚的位置
contains the location of the Rabbit's Foot.
我要你去把它拿来给我 我要的是那个兔脚
You're going to get it and bring it to me. The Rabbit's Foot.
伊森上次碰面的时候我记得你有只手表
Ethan, you had a watch last time I saw you.
我给你48小时 按我的表开始计时
You have 48 hours, starting on my mark.
等等 等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
好了 等你弄到手了 打我这个电话
Now, call me at this number when you have it.
- 等等 - 拿兔脚来换朱莉娅的命
- Just wait. - Julia's life for the Rabbit's Foot.
- 48小时交货 否则她就没命了 - 等等！等等 等等！
- You have 48 hours, or she dies. - Wait! Wait. Wait.
1-116所有部门就位
Condition 1-116. All units on scene.
跟我们回去 伊森
We need you to come with us.
但是… 皮特 这是怎么回事？
Just… Pete, what the hell is this?
我很抱歉 亨特先生 我奉命带你回去
Sorry about that, Mr. Hunt. We were told to bring you in.
- 好吧 - 那就上车吧
- Okay. - Get ready to transport.
啊 嗨 但现在不行
Whoa. Hey. Just not right now.
- 告诉头儿你来了 但是… - 伊森 上车
- Just tell them you came and that… - Ethan. Get in.
我们不想在这使用暴力 但你知道我们不得不用 伊森进来
We don't want to use force here, and you know we will. Ethan, get in.
- 告诉他们你来过这儿… - 伊森！
- Tell them that you came here… - Ethan!
…但是你们到之前我已经走了 OK？
…and that I left already, okay?
站住！
Freeze!
伊森 站住！站住 伊森！
Ethan, stop! Stop, Ethan!
好 铐住他的手
Yeah. Get his hands.
我看了下你柏林行动的记录
I reviewed the transcript of your Berlin operation.
很有意思
It's very interesting.
看来法瑞斯探员那掌握了一些…
It seems that Agent Farris had some information
她只想和你单独分享的情报 并没有打算把它共享给组织
she wished to share with you but not with this agency.
一些你没能上报的东西
Something you failed to report.
未经正当手续审批 你就私自去了梵蒂冈行动
You ordered the Vatican operation without proper approvals.
那次任务最终导致了 敌人对我们灾难式的还击
That mission resulted in a catastrophic attack.
但是你居然此后就隐居幕后了
And then you fled the scene.
但是我可不是一个可以 被任意欺负的局外人
Now, I am not a stranger to disrespect.
没有经过深度的研究 你大概不知道我的处境
You don't get to where I am without developing a thick skin.
但让我不能忍受的是
But what I won't stand for,
而且让我睡不着觉的是
what I will lose sleep over, and I love my sleep,
一个没有责任心的流氓探员捣乱 我可是爱睡觉的人
is the idea of an irresponsible rogue agent working in my office.
现在开始我要把所有的事情都扶上正轨
So I'm going to slow things way down here.
你可以看着我
You can look at me
用你那审判、控诉的眼神 如你所愿
with those judgmental, incriminating eyes all you want,
我不是信口开河
but I bullshit you not.
我会不惜一切代价来保卫我的祖国
I will bleed on the flag to make sure the stripes stay red.
我不知道怎么跟你说
I don't know what to say to you.
布拉塞尔说对了 你已经情绪失控了
Brassel's right. You're out of control.
看着我
Look at me.
伊森你起码要表现出和他人谈话时应有的礼貌
Ethan, at least show me the courtesy of looking at me when I'm talking to you.
我截听到了戴维安的电话 知道了他要用朱莉娅的命去换兔脚
I intercepted Daviars call. I know he wants the Rabbit's Foot for Julia's life.
只是…
It's just…
这真是
This is
太让人失望了
so disappointing.
去上海丰山公寓1406号
Go to Shanghai. Feng Shan Apartments… 1406.
我希望我能做些什么帮帮你 但…
I wish there was something I could do to help you, but…
带他去禁闭室
Take him to the holding cell.
我来了
No, I'm on it.
长官 不必紧张 我会抓他回来
Yes, sir. There's no need to panic. I'll get him back.
长官？ 伊森·亨特…
Sir? Ethan Hunt…
我知道了 把电台给我
I know what happened. Give me the radio.
我是布拉塞尔指挥官 伊森·亨特正试图逃走
This is Director Brassel. Ethan Hunt is attempting to escape the building.
他现在在西货运电梯里 尽一切可能拦住他
He's in the west cargo elevator. He must be stopped.
马上去把门多萨和格拉汉姆带到观察室来
I want Mendoza and Graham in the situation room right away.
长官 我已经下令封锁整栋大楼了
I'm having the building surrounded, sir.
所有入口都有我们的人
I've got units posted at all the entrances.
我是布拉塞尔 我要求6号戒严 我重复一次
This is Brassel again. I'm ordering a code-six lockdown. I repeat.
- 是亨特 - 我知道是他
- It's Hunt. - I know it's Hunt.
亨特在地下二层9号
Hunt was flagged on sub-basement nine.
所有保安人员立即赶过去
I want all security personnel down there now.
安全信道堵住了
Security channel's jammed.
肯定是亨特按住了发送按钮
Hunt must be holding down the transmit button.
你在跟我开玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
广播最后一遍通知 前往赫尔辛基的1162号航班从46号门登机
Last call for flight 1162 for Helsinki, now boarding at gate 46.
最后一次呼叫鲍尔先生 最后一次呼叫鲍尔先生
Final call for Mr. Bower. Final call for Mr. Bower.
请到4号门登机
Please come to gate 4.
- 帕维尔·索博卡先生 - 索博卡
- Mr. Pavel Sobo… Sobotka. - Sobotka.
索博卡好的 你要飞往上海？
Sobotka. Okay. And you're flying to Shanghai?
对不起 我不懂捷克语 让我看看你的航班
I don't speak Czech. I'm sorry. Let's see about your flight.
好的
Okay.
- 好 - 好的
- Okay. - Okay.
（中国 上海）
别杀我
Don't kill me.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
对不起
马斯格雷夫告诉了我们关于朱莉娅被绑架的消息 我们是赶来帮忙的
Musgrave told us about Julia. We're here to help.
要救你妻子 你必须要有兔脚
To get your wife, you'll need the Rabbit's Foot.
根据戴维安公文包里找到的计划
According to the plans from Daviars briefcase,
它在衡山宾馆56层的一个实验室里
it's in a laboratory on the 56th floor of the Hengshan Lu Building.
这次行动的种种情况真像恶梦一般
Which is a nightmare for just about every reason.
只知道那个接头人是中国军方的人员 我们没有支援部队以及更加详细的资料
They're a Chinese military contractor. We have no pull, no details.
好消息是 不管它是什么
The good news is, whatever it is,
兔脚很小 我们可以偷过来
the Rabbit Foot's small, so we can steal it.
坏消息就在于 我们必须偷
The bad news, we got to steal it.
从盗贼的角度看 这次的偷盗计划真是失败
From a thief's point of view, this is worst-case scenario.
警卫都是秘密特工
The security guards are all privately-contracted
以前都是人民解放军
former People's Liberation Army.
通向实验室的唯一通道是那部私人电梯
The only access to the lab is by private elevator.
它只能由实验室内的人启动
And that can only be activated by persons inside the lab.
大楼每个角落都被监视器监控着
All of it surveilled by security cameras within the building.
楼顶呢？
What about the roof?
4个警卫全天守卫 两边顶楼各两个
Four guards full time. Two on each rooftop.
跟这比起来 兰利就是小儿科
Langley was a cakewalk compared to this.
没错
That's the one.
- 这楼多高？ - 什么意思？
- How tall is that building? - Why?
最高点离地162米
It's 162 meters at the highest point.
那左边的楼有多高？
What about that, the building on the left? How tall is that one?
地图上标注是226米
Says 226 meters.
226米 那么两栋楼之间的距离呢？
226. Distance between the buildings?
横向距离47.55米
47.55 meters across.
伊森？
Ethan?
很不错 我想这够高了
That's good. I think it's tall enough.
- 要干嘛？ - 做支点
- For what? - A fulcrum.
你要荡过去… 不…等等…
Oh, you're gonna swing… No, no, no, no. Wait, wait.
- 你可能会碰到房顶后再弹起来 - 对 有可能
- You could bounce right off the roof. - Yes, I could.
即使你在屋顶上成功着陆并且干掉警卫
Even if you made it to the rooftop, took out the guards,
拿了兔脚你也很难走出大厅 你想好了退路吗？
and got the Rabbit's Foot, you can't just walk out of the lobby. What's your exit?
从顶上蹦下来 我需要一个降落伞
Base-jump off the top. I need a chute.
即使在162米 但跳跃所需高度仍不够
Even at 162, you're pushing minimum height for a jump.
如果降落伞打开得慢一点 你就死定了
Chute opens any lower than that and you're dead.
你准备怎么做？
What are you going to do?
在上海市中心着落 并且期望没人看见？
Land in the middle of Shanghai and hope no one notices?
还要跑到两个街区外的中央公园
Central Park's two blocks away.
等等 伊森 我虽然没有更好的主意
Wait, wait, Ethan, I'm not saying I have a better idea,
但是我要说的是 天才和白痴往往只有一线之差
but there's a point where bold becomes stupid.
现在我们甚至还不知道那东西是什么
Now, we don't even know what this thing is, and you're talking
而你却要把它交给一个 为恐怖分子提供消息的人手里
about handing it over to a guy who provides terrorists with information.
卢瑟我们当然不直接交给他们
Luther, of course I'm not suggesting that we just hand it over.
到时我们在兔脚上做些手脚 就能跟踪它了
We're going to tag the Rabbit's Foot so we can trace it and know where it is.
我们这就能装上 然后我亲自送去
Now, you know we can get that gear here. I just deliver it myself.
之后我们就可以联系马斯格雷夫 让IMF进行跟踪 布下天罗地网
We contact Musgrave, have the IMF trace a tag, order a raid,
把兔脚夺回来并且逮捕戴维安
get the Rabbit's Foot back, grab Davian.
如果我救回了朱莉娅 我们就赢了
Now, if I get out with Julia, we win.
如果我没有 那…
If I don't, then…
听着 如果她不幸被杀 我也不想活了
Look, then she's dead anyway. And so am I.
你知道？
You know?
该死的 现在是8：11 8：12了
Goddamn it, it's 8:11, it's 8:12.
还有2个小时 他们就要杀死我妻子了
And we have two hours before they kill my wife.
你们参加还是不参加？
Are you in or not?
当然 我们参加
Of course we're in.
你有18分钟时间
You got 18 minutes.
你要搞定这一切
You're going to make it over there.
你找到兔脚 回到屋顶
You're going to find the Rabbit's Foot, get back to the roof,
当你准备好跳了 无线电通知我
radio me when you're ready to make the jump,
我们来接你
and we're going to come get you.
谢谢你来帮我
Thank you for coming.
这是我的份内事
That's my job.
行动
Batter up.
好了 他们有反应了 继续
Oh, yeah. They're freaking out. Hit them again.
好的
Okay.
他成功了
He made it.
我就知道他能搞定
I knew he'd make it.
我进去了 5分钟后出来
I'm going in. I'll be out in five minutes.
- 12分钟了 - 他还剩5分钟
- It's been 12 minutes. - He's got five minutes left.
他5分钟内不给戴维安打电话 朱莉娅就完了
If he doesn't call Davian in five minutes, Julia's dead.
有进展么？
Anything?
没有
Negative.
你呢？ 有好消息么？
How about you? Any good news?
没有 一无所获
No, nothing.
伊森 快啊
Come on, Ethan.
那是什么？
What is that?
小时候我养了只猫 它总是逃跑
When I was little I had a cat, and he used to run away all the time.
我经常如此祈祷 它就能自动回来
And it's just a prayer I'd say to bring him home.
教我怎么说
Teach it to me.
我拿到了兔脚 但我没法回到屋顶去
I've got the Rabbit's Foot, but I can't make it to the roof.
这什么意思？ 你在哪？
What the hell do you mean you can't make it to the roof? Where are you?
看上面！往上看 往上看！
Look up! Look up, look up!
- 该死 - 太低了
- Oh, shit. - He's way too low.
- 伊森！快上车！他们追来了！- 谁？
- Ethan! Get in! They're coming! - Who?
大楼的警卫 他们都发飙了
Building security, and they're pissed.
好的 快走…
Okay. Go, go, go, go.
你还剩多少时间？
How much time you got left?
不到2分钟
Less than two minutes.
你得带我们离开这 手机没有信号了
You gotta get us out of here. I lost the signal.
- 你还好么？ - 不太好
- You okay? - Not yet.
快！
Come on. Come on.
没有信号 没有信号
I don't have a signal. I don't have a signal.
马上到了 马上到了
I'm on it. I'm on it. I'm on it!
珍！
Zhen!
该死的 对不起
Damn it. I'm sorry.
一直按住这个键
Put pressure on it.
- 收到信号的时候告我 - 你在干嘛？
- Tell me when you get a signal. - What are you doing?
收到了！
I got a signal!
按重播键
Hit redial.
你只剩5秒了 你知道么？
You only had five seconds left. Do you realize that?
我拿到兔脚了
The Rabbit's Foot. I have it.
敦安中路火车站广场 在那等我 只许你一个人来
The train yard at Dunan Zhong Lu. Wait for me there. Alone.
- 怎样？ - 安全
- Yeah? - Go secure.
我们安全了
We are.
我拿到了兔脚
I have the Rabbit's Foot.
- 你还好吗？ - 我在调试追踪器
- You okay? - I'm tagging it now.
开始追踪吧 不要让这只脚在我们视线内消失
You need to run a trace. Make sure we have eyes on this thing.
- 号码多少？ - 6-3-9-6-4-1
- What's the tag? - 6-3-9-6-4-1.
找到了
Got it.
我看到你在峦桃路
I see you on Luang Tao Lu Road.
如果8个小时内联系不到我 你就派军队过来追踪这个东西
If you don't hear from me in eight hours, you send an army after this thing.
- 好运 - 你也是
- Good luck. - You, too.
- 马斯格雷夫先生 - 对
- Mr. Musgrave. - Yeah.
我昨天下午注意到
It's come to my attention that yesterday afternoon
你派遣了一支队伍去远东
you sent a team to the Far East.
我们收到情报 哈达姆·萨利姆·巴哈
We received intel that Hadaam Saleen Bahar
正在去上海的路上
was en route to Shanghai.
- 哈达姆·萨利姆·巴哈 - 对
- Hadaam Saleen Bahar. - That's right.
知道我想干什么吗？ 我想看看那个内部情报
You know what I'd love? I'd love to see that intel.
- 发到我办公室来 - 是的 长官
- I'll be in my office. - Yes, sir.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
回家见
I'll see you back home.
伊森
Ethan.
你知道他们可能打算把你俩都杀死
You know they probably plan to kill you both.
我们如何能「回家见」
Then I won't see you back home.
希望你能回来
Better get back.
喝了它 别问问题
Drink it. No questions.
早上好
Good morning.
朱莉娅
Jules.
我们在你脑袋植入了爆炸装置
We've put an explosive charge in your head.
听起来耳熟吧
Does that sound familiar?
兔脚在哪？
The Rabbit's Foot. Where is it?
我把它给你了
I gave it to you.
我数10下
Now, I'm going to count to 10
告诉我兔脚在哪！
and you're going to tell me where the Rabbit's Foot is
否则 她就死了
or she dies.
我们应该有很多话要聊 不是吗？
Seems we have a lot to talk about. Don't we?
- 你以为我在跟你玩游戏么？ - 你个婊子养的！
- Do you think I'm playing? - Son of a bitch!
你以为我真不敢开枪？
Do you think I'm playing? You don't think I'll do it?
东西在哪？
Where is it?
- 看着我 - 东西到底在哪？
- Look at me. - Where the hell is it?
- 看着我 挺住 - 7！
- Look at me. Stay with me. - Seven!
我要杀了你！我对天发誓 我一定要…
I am going to kill you. I swear to God I'm going to…
- 8 - 不 不要！
- Eight! - No, please.
求你 不要 放过她吧！
Please. Don't do this. Just let her go.
我答应你 我对你发誓
I promise you. I promise you.
- 无论如何我都会想办法弄到… - 9
- I can figure out how to get whatever… - Nine.
听我说 我可以帮你拿到任何你想要的…
Listen to me. I want to help you get whatever you want.
但你千万不能胡作非为 你应该知道怎么做
But you got to do what's right. What you know is right.
求你了…
No, please…
不要
No.
- 10 - 不要！
- Ten. - Don't!
他已经被我逼上了梁山 我知道 他没说谎
I pushed him as far as he can go. I know he's not lying.
我懂
I understand.
我还有些疑问 我想先问问他
I've got some questions I want to ask him first.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
只打开罐子看看不能解决问题
You can't just open the canister.
我们必须确认你带来的是真货
We had to make sure you brought the real thing.
我们现在确定了兔脚是真货
The Rabbit's Foot. Now we know.
你别碰她！你别碰她！
Don't you touch her! Don't you touch her!
戴维安的翻译 他的警卫队长
Daviars translator, his Head of Security.
记得么？在梵蒂冈她没保护好他
Remember? At the Vatican she failed him.
伊森 朱莉娅还活着
Ethan, Julia is still alive.
戴维安想把你俩都杀了 但我说服了他
Davian wanted to kill you both, but I convinced him otherwise.
朱莉娅没见过我 她什么也不知道 她是无辜的
Julia hasn't seen me. She doesn't know anything. She's clean.
她可以继续享受生活
She can go on to have a life.
只要你告诉我 林赛对你说了些什么
As long as you tell me, what was in Lindsey's message?
我知道她从柏林给你寄了块微型芯片
I know she sent you a microdot from Berlin.
林赛知道我和戴维安么？
Did Lindsey know about me and Davian?
那就是她给你发消息的原因么？ 你看了么？
Is that why she sent the message to you? Did you read it?
还有其它人看过它么？
Did anyone else see it?
她知道我在干什么吗？
Did she know about the work I was doing?
我还可以跟IMF妥协吗？
Could I be compromised at IMF?
伊森 伊森
Ethan. Ethan.
她是不是以为布拉塞尔陷害了她？
Did she buy that Brassel set her up?
她上当了吗？
Did she buy that?
原来是你告的密
You told him.
所以戴维安知道林赛来了
That's how Davian knew Lindsey was coming.
你告的密
You told him.
我以为你会救她回来
I thought you could get her back.
但是我不准备让布拉塞尔的人毁掉我所做的一切
But I wasrt gonna let Brassel, of all people, undo the work I'd done.
我自行决定采取行动 伊森 这是为了我国人民
I took action, Ethan, on behalf of the working families of our country.
军队 还有白宫的利益
The Armed Forces, the White House.
我已经受够了布拉塞尔他那伪君子作风
I'd had enough of Brassel and his sanctimony.
IMF执行主任 他就像个侍卫一样唯命是从
IMF Executive Director. He's an affirmative action poster boy.
你按他要求逮捕戴维安 又能怎样？
You grab Davian like he wanted, then what?
戴维安就像野草
Daviars a weed.
你们今天抓了他 明天就会有更多的戴维安出现
You cut him out, two more spring up just like him the next day.
逮捕他？ 然后呢？
Arrest him? Then what?
你们利用他
You use him.
和他合作
Collaborate with him.
这才是上策
And it's Christmas.
18小时后 兔脚就会被送到
In 18 hours, the Rabbit's Foot will be delivered
中东买家的手里 我们的情报机构会发现这一点
to its Middle Eastern buyer, and we'll have credible intel to prove it.
明天的这个时候 美国安全理事会将得到这次行动的报告
US Security Council will get a report by this time tomorrow.
一星期后我们国家会采取军事袭击
We're talking a military strike within a week.
当一切都尘埃落定
And when the sand settles,
我们祖国就会使出它最擅长的技能
our country will do what it does best.
摧毁敌人 他们都不得不乖乖地听我们的
Clean up. Infrastructure.
民主取得伟大胜利
Democracy wins.
林赛的消息里面到底说了些什么？
What was Lindsey's message?
告诉我 朱莉娅就会被释放
You tell me, and Julia walks.
你只需要演完这最后一出戏
It's the only play you have left.
除非我听到她的声音 不然无法确认她还活着
Not till I hear her voice, know she's alive.
当然可以
Of course.
让她听电话
Put her on.
- 朱莉娅？ - 伊森？
- Jules? - Ethan?
我们见面时那里有座山 山边有个湖
When we met, there was a lake near the mountain.
那个湖叫什么名字
What was the lake called?
瓦纳卡
Wanaka.
伊森 求你了
Please, Ethan.
- 朱莉娅 - 伊森 我不明白…
- Jules. - Ethan, I don't understand…
本杰明·杜恩
Benjamin Dunne.
班吉 是我
Benji, it's me.
- 伊森 - 什么？ 不会吧 真的么？
- Ethan. - What? No. Really?
仔细听我说 我需要你的帮助
Listen to me very carefully. I need your help.
我需要追踪这部手机 最后一次通话时的地址
I need to trace the location of the last call made from this phone.
听着 不 伊森 嘘！
Look, no. Ethan. Shush.
他们在… 全世界都在找你
They're looking… Everyone's looking for you.
我知道的所有人 他们都在找… 我刚才查找了一下
Everyone I know. They're looking… I just looked it up.
现在 你已经成为头号通缉犯了
Okay, you're on Interpol's most wanted list.
顺便说一句 是那种公开通缉的名单上
And that, by the way, is a spectacular list to be on.
不管怎么样了 很抱歉 我现在得挂掉了
Whatever happened, I'm sorry, but I'm hanging up now right now.
班吉 我现在没时间跟你解释
Benji, I don't have time for this.
你知道发生了什么事吗？ 我被陷害了
What do you think happened? I've been set up.
我很喜欢自己的这份工作 非常的热爱
I think I like my job. Okay? A lot.
你知道他们会给我们的通话录音
All right? And you know they're gonna be taping this call.
你知道怎么删掉的通话内容的 我现在给你号码
And you know you can erase it. I'm giving you the number right now.
- 你准备好了吗？ - 好吧 等等
- Are you ready? - All right. Just hang on.
我可能为这把居民权都会丢掉 你知道的
I'm gonna lose my citizenship because of this, you know.
7-3-4-4-2-5-6-4-3-6-7
7-3-4-4-2-5-6-4-3-6-7.
好的 别挂电话
Okay. Wait. Okay. Hold the line, please.
- 你还在？ - 在
- Are you there? - Yeah.
好了
Okay.
也许干完了我们就可以 一块儿蹲牢房了 明白吗？
Maybe we can share a jail cell together, you know?
如果事态没有转机就这样发展的话
If this all goes tits up, which it will.
号码的位置是上海
The location of that number is Shanghai.
对了 就是上海
There, I just told you. Shanghai.
我刚刚帮助了国家的敌人 真是梦幻啊 谢谢你
I've just aided and abetted an enemy of the state. Fantastic. Thank you.
我就在他旁边吗？ 用我这部电话来确认下我的位置
Am I close? Use this phone to track my location.
对了 他就在你旁边！
Oh, you're there. Well, you're close.
有多接近？ 信号在这个房子里么？
How close? Is the signal in the building?
不 不是从那来的
No, no, no. It isn't coming from there.
它来自东北方向1英里以外的一个房子
It's in a building one mile to the northeast.
班吉就用电话指引我过去
Benji, lead me to the signal.
我有个小小的问题 你在上海干嘛？
There is one thing. What the hell are you doing in Shanghai?
我跟你见面时候再告你
I'll tell you when I see you.
你… 往北
What you… You need to go north.
应该看到一座桥 上去 过桥
Okay, there's a bridge. Get to it, cross it.
左转 沿着河走四分之三英里
Make a left. Go three-quarters of a mile along the river.
我找到了
I got it. I got it.
好 那就对了 往前走 往前走
Good, good. That's right. Keep going. Keep going.
左转两次
Make your next left and then the next one.
然后随着那条马路直走1000码
And then follow that down 1, 000 yards.
一千码
A thousand yards.
- 好 - 好拉 左转 左
- Okay. Okay, okay. - Okay, okay. Left. Left.
对 很好 继续走
Yeah, that's good. That's good. Keep going. Keep going.
好的 现在…嗨
Okay, now look… Hiya. Hi.
班吉 哪里？
Benji, where?
- 班吉？ 我往哪走？ - 现在右转
- Benji? Which way do I go? - Now take a right.
好 继续 再左转
Okay. Go down, left.
左？ 我正往左走
Left? I'm going left.
好
Good, good.
在你左手边的第二幢建筑物
It's in the second building on your left.
信号在这里面3米左右的距离中忽强忽弱
The signal bearing's plus or minus three meters
在东北角上
from the northeast corner.
今天欠你个人情
I owe you.
朱莉娅 朱莉娅
Jules. Jules.
你不会有事的
You're gonna be okay.
天啊
Oh, God!
天啊！
God!
我已经激活了你脑袋里的装置
I've activated the charge in your head.
你只能活大概4分钟的时间了
You have maybe four minutes left.
我告诉过你吗？ 她一直在呼喊你的名字
Didrt I tell you she'd call out your name?
伊森 伊森
Ethan. Ethan.
不要
No.
求你
Please.
我早就跟你说过 我要在她面前杀了你
And I told you I was going to kill you in front of her?
好了 我还是现在你面前把她给杀了
Well, I'm going to kill her in front of you.
伊森？
Ethan?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
伊森 我不明白发生了什么事
I don't understand what's going on, Ethan.
- 我知道 冷静 - 那些人想让你干什么？
- I know. I know. Just wait. - What do those men want from you?
- 你为什么也会来到这里？ - 你怎么找到我的？
- Why are we here? - How did you find me?
伊森 告诉我这是怎么回事？
Please, Ethan. What the hell is going on?
你还好么？
Are you okay?
伊森 怎么了？天啊
Ethan, what's wrong? Okay. Oh, God.
我会告诉你发生的一切 你现在只要待在我身旁即可
I'm going to tell you everything. You just stay with me.
伊森 怎么回事？ 你在找什么？
Ethan. What's happening? What are you looking for?
- 我们必须离开这里 - 现在还不行
- We've got to get out of here. - Not yet.
- 这里没有 - 什么什么？
- They don't have one! - What?
- 自动减颤器 - 自动减颤器？
- A defibrillator. - A defibrillator?
伊森？
Ethan?
伊森？那些人是干什么的？ 我们在这里干什么？
Ethan? Who are these people? What the hell are we doing here?
太棒了！
Good!
这是一把贝雷特92F式手枪
This is a Beretta 92F.
是非常精准的近距离武器
It's a very accurate, close-range weapon.
- 别对着我 - 对不起
- Don't point it at me. - Sorry.
它有15发子弹
It holds 15 rounds.
枪膛空了后 把弹舱滑上去并这样子锁上
When the mag is empty, the slide will lock back like this.
你怎么知道这些这么多？
How do you know so much about this?
上膛的时候
To reload, push this button.
空弹夹会掉出来 向后拉这个滑块
The empty mag falls out
你把新的推进去
and you shove the other one in,
就像给厨房里的聚光灯换电池一样
like the batteries in the flashlight in the kitchen,
然后拉这里上膛
then release the slide.
- 为什么给我枪？ - 可能还会有其他人来这里威胁我们
- Why are you giving me a gun? - There could be others.
如果你开枪的时候 记得尽量低一些
If you have to use it, you stay low.
确认是敌人后 瞄准然后开枪
You identify your enemy. Point and shoot.
很简单 瞄准然后开枪
It's very simple. Point and shoot.
退后
Stand back.
很好
Good.
我脑袋里有爆破装置 你必须杀了我 不然我就会被这个装置干掉
I have a charge in my head. I'm going to die unless you kill me.
- 什么？ - 把电闸开关各一次
- What? - Throw the switch on and off.
- 别忘了关掉 - 我做不到
- Don't forget the off. - I can't do that.
你一定可以把我救活 我一定会活过来
You can bring me back. I'll come back.
- 我做不到 - 你必须做到 已经没有时间了
- I can't. - You have to! There's no time!
来吧！求你了！
Now! Please!
等等…我爱你
Wait, wait! Wait. Wait. I love you.
我爱你！
I love you.
天啊
Oh, God.
快醒来 亲爱的！
Come on, baby.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight…
9 10 11 12 13 14 15
Nine, ten, eleven, twelve, thirteen, fourteen, fifteen.
醒来吧 亲爱的 快点醒来
Come on, baby. I need you to come back.
我需要你
I need you back.
天啊
Oh, God.
这些都是你的杰作？
You did that?
哇
Wow.
我当时只在想…
So, I was just thinking…
我在想你也许想告诉我 为什么我们现在会在中国
I was thinking you might want to tell me why we're in China.
我知道
I know.
我…
I…
我在一个机构供职
I work for an agency.
这机构名叫IMF
It's called IMF.
IMF代表什么意思？
What does that stand for?
不可能任务部队
Lmpossible Mission Force.
胡说
Shut up.
确实是的 我没开玩笑
No, I'm not kidding.
你不懂 我告诉你的这些都是绝对机密
You don't understand. Everything I'm telling you is top-secret.
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我对你所做的一切表示感谢
Just wanna show my appreciation for your work.
如果有什么要我赔偿的话 就打电话
Call it reparations for anything I might have put you through.
我刚和白宫方面联系过了
You should know the White House has contacted me.
他们非常想与你谈谈工作的事情
Now, there's a job that they are
十分希望能跟你聊聊
very interested in speaking with you about.
谢谢
Thank you,
但我现在有更多的东西需要仔细思考
but I have a lot to think about.
你没打算退出吧？伊森？
You aren't considering quitting, are you, Ethan?
我在计划我的蜜月旅行
I'm considering going on my honeymoon.
- 好好玩 - 谢谢
- Have fun. - Thank you.
好的
Yeah.
对了 还有件事
Hey, one thing.
兔脚到底是什么？
The Rabbit's Foot. What is it?
答应我你会留下来 那我就告诉你
Promise me you'll stay, I'll tell you.
- 我会给你寄张明信片 - 够公平
- I'll send you a postcard. - Fair enough.